allpaws.com 2018-10-03

# Privacy Policy | PetSmart Charities

**General and Donor Privacy Policy**

PetSmart Charities® wants you to know how we collect, use, share and protect information about you.  By interacting with us, you consent to our use of information that is collected or submitted as we describe in this privacy policy.  We may change or add to this privacy policy, so we urge you to review it periodically. This policy applies only to residents of the United States. If you are a resident of Canada, please click [here](https://www.petsmartcharities.ca/privacy-policy) for applicable information.

## What Information is Collected

## Types of personal information we collect include:

  * Your name
  * Your mailing address
  * Your e-mail address
  * Your phone (or mobile) number
  * Your credit/debit card number
  * Your donation information
  * Your date of birth or age
  * Your location
  * Your pet’s information (name, breed, date of birth, gender, veterinary information, photographs, etc.)

## If you choose not to provide personal information, we may not be able to provide you with requested services or information.  

### Automated Information Collection

We may connect information collected automatically with information we may already have about you.  If we are able to identify you as a PetSmart Charities supporter, we may, for example, link your activity on our website to your activity in one of our Adoptions Centers.  This allows us to provide you with a personalized experience regardless of how you interact with us – online, in-person, mobile, etc.

### PetSmart Charities Automated Information Collection

We and our Service Providers use cookies, web beacons, and other technologies to receive and store certain types of information whenever you interact with us through your computer or mobile device.  This information, which includes the pages you visit on our site, which web address you came from, the type of device you are using, donation information, search terms and geographic location, helps us recognize you, customize your website experience and make our outreach efforts more relevant.  These technologies also enable us to provide features such as text (SMS/MMS) messages you have chosen to receive.  We also use Flash cookies for fraud prevention and other purposes.

In order to provide the best online experience possible, we also use these technologies for reporting and analysis purposes, such as how you are using our website, performance of our outreach efforts, and your response to those outreach efforts.

### Third-Party Automated Information Collection

In certain instances, we allow third-party organizations to collect certain information from you when you visit our website and to use that information to provide requested services and information to you.  These parties typically use a cookie or a third party web beacon to collect this information.

### Mobile App and Mobile Website

If you access the PetSmart Charities website through a mobile device, the same type of information outlined throughout this policy may be collected.

### User Experience Information

In order to improve your online experience, help with fraud identification, and to assist our representatives in resolving issues you may experience in completing online donations or other online activities on our site, we use tools to monitor certain user experience information; including login information, IP address, data regarding pages visited and specific actions taken on pages visited (e.g., information entered during donation process), and browser information.

### Social Media Widgets

PetsmartCharities.org includes social media features, such as the Facebook interactive buttons, Google Plus, YouTube, Instagram and Twitter widgets.  These features may collect information about your IP address and which page you’re visiting on our site, and they may set a cookie to make sure the feature functions properly.  Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our site.  Your interactions with those features are governed by the privacy policies of the companies that provide them.

### Information from Other Sources

We may collect data that’s publicly available.  For example, information you submit in a public forum (e.g., a blog, chat room, or social media) can be read, collected, or used by us and others, and could be used to personalize your experience.  You are responsible for the information you choose to submit in these instances.

We also may obtain information provided by third parties.  For instance, we may obtain information from organizations that can enhance our existing supporter information to improve the accuracy and add to the information we have about our supporters (for example, adding address information).  This improves our ability to contact you and increases the relevance of our outreach efforts by providing better information that may interest you.

### Facility Cameras

PetSmart Charities’ Adoption Centers sometimes occupy space within PetSmart stores.  In-store cameras are used for security and operational purposes such as measuring and observing customer traffic patterns. You may access the PetSmart, Inc. Privacy Policy by clicking [here](https://www.petsmart.com/helpdeskcategory/-helpdesk-safety-category-helpdesk_category_cmp_20121219_173952?article=helpdesk_landing_article_privacy_policy_cmp_20120808_142218).

### Geo-Location Tracking

Certain mobile devices contain geo-location tracking capability.  We may use such capability or other geo-location tracking technology for outreach and analytical purposes.

## How Your Information is Used

Examples of how we may use the information we collect include (but are not limited to):

### Donations and Services Fulfillment

  * Process donations or requests for information about our services on our website, or to otherwise serve you
  * Connect within PetSmart Charities regarding our mission via personnel contact, e-mail, or on social media platforms
  * Administer sweepstakes and contests
  * Connect you with third parties that perform certain services in connection with PetSmart Charities (such as animal rescue or spay/neuter organizations)

### Our Outreach Purposes

  * Deliver newsletters, e-mails, mobile messages, and social media notifications
  * Provide interactive features of the website or mobile applications, such as outreach communications and other information regarding our services and activities.
  * Administer outreach surveys and focus groups

### Internal Operations

  * Improve the effectiveness of our website, mobile experience, and outreach efforts
  * Conduct research and analysis
  * Perform other activities as needed, or as described elsewhere in this privacy policy

### Photographs and Information about Your Pet

  * Photographs of your pet may be taken and used for our internal recordkeeping purposes, to share with you or your designated family members/agents via email or text, or to facilitate our outreach efforts (for example, in social media)
  * We may maintain information about your pet for our internal recordkeeping purposes or to facilitate our outreach efforts
  * Your pet’s name may also be uploaded to our database and associated with your name

### Fraud Prevention

  * Prevent fraudulent activity
  * Monitor against theft
  * Protect our visitors and supporters, and our charitable operations and assets

### Legal Compliance

  * Investigate claims, incidents or inquiries regarding supporters, associates, vendors, pets and pet adopters
  * Assist law enforcement, animal control, health officials and other government entities to respond to legal, regulatory, health and similar inquiries

## How Your Information is Shared

### Donors

When you make a donation to PetSmart Charities we will collect your name, mailing address, phone number, e-mail address and billing information, as well as credit/debit card information. This information enables us to contact you in the event of payment processing difficulties, verify or respond to your donation, and deliver services and information about PetSmart Charities to you. If you authorize us to do so, we will retain your credit/debit card information to process recurring payment transactions.

PetSmart Charities will not sell, trade or share a donor’s personal information with anyone else nor send donor mailings on behalf of other organizations, unless a donor has given PetSmart Charities specific permission to do so.  We may share information in limited circumstances as described in this Policy, including the following:

  * When necessary for Legal Requirements as described in this Policy
  * When applicable for regulatory purposes (such as annual IRS filings on Form 990)
  * With Service Providers who we engage to support our own internal operations and administration – in these cases, the Service Providers are required to maintain confidentiality of donor information, and they are prohibited from selling, trading or sharing such information with anyone else

### PetSmart Charities and Associated Organizations

We share the information we collect within PetSmart Charities.  We also share information with organizations that are closely associated with PetSmart Charities, such as PetSmart, Inc., PetSmart Store Support Group, Inc., PetSmart Puerto Rico, PetSmart Charities of Canada and PETM Canada Corporation (“Associate Organizations”). PetSmart Charities and these entities may use this information to contact you about information and charitable opportunities that may be of interest to you or for other outreach purposes.

### Service Providers

We may share the information we collect with organizations that provide internal operations and administrative support services to us (such as printers, e-mail marketers, mobile marketers, analytics providers, web hosting providers, call center service providers, sweepstakes vendors, payment processors, or data enhancement providers) (“Service Providers”) or help us with our outreach efforts.  These organizations may need information about you in order to perform their functions. If we share your personal information with these organizations, it is on a confidential basis and the Service Providers are not authorized to use the personal information we share with them for any purpose other than providing services for PetSmart Charities.

### Legal Requirements

We may disclose information we collect when we believe disclosure is appropriate to comply with the law; to enforce or apply applicable terms and conditions and other agreements; or to protect the rights, property or safety of our organization, our supporters, pets in the care of organizations that we work with, the public or others.

### Elsewhere at Your Direction

At your direction or request, we may share your information. 

### Sharing with Other Organizations (for their outreach purposes)

We may communicate to you information from other organizations.  In such cases, we do not provide your personal information to them and they will not know your identity unless you choose to transact with them, in which case their privacy policies will govern your relationship.  With your consent, we may share your personal information with other organizations that are not part of PetSmart Charities.  These organizations may use the information we share to provide special opportunities to you.

### Sharing Aggregate Information with Third Parties

We may share aggregate non-personally identifiable information (information that does not directly identify an individual) with third parties for any lawful purpose.

### Asset Transfers

If some or all of our assets are sold or transferred, we may transfer the corresponding information regarding our supporters.  We also may retain a copy of that supporter information.

## What Choices You Have

### Opt-Out Choices

You may “opt out” of certain PetSmart Charities outreach communications.  Most of our communications are sent by email and direct mail, though you may also opt out of other types of communications. You may also access or change your personal information or ask us to do so.

**To opt-out yourself:**

  * Follow opt-out “unsubscribe” instructions in outreach e-mails we send to you.
  * Log on to PetSmartCharities.org to access and change your profile information and preferences if you have an online account with us.
  * Set the _Help_ function of your browser to not receive cookies.  Please note this may make it difficult or impossible to take certain actions on PetSmartCharities.org.
  * Text STOP to text messages (SMS/MMS) we send to you.
  * Contact us as described in Questions or Concerns below. Please include your full name, address, phone number and e-mail address. Also, tell us what information you would like to access, change or add to our “opt out” list. This will help us process your request.

If you “opt out” of PetSmart Charities’ communications, you may continue to receive communications from PetSmart Charities and its Service Providers such as donation confirmations, communications directly related to a pet adopted through our Adoption Centers, and other specific administrative information related to your relationship with PetSmart Charities. Your information will remain in our database marked as inactive so that you no longer receive outreach materials from us.

**If you need our help:**

  * Call us at 1-800-423-PETS (7387) (U.S. residents) and tell them which information you would like to access or which types of contacts you want to opt out of. Please note you may need to speak with a manager.
  * **E-mail:**  [info[at]petsmartcharities[dot]org](https://web.archive.org/geo-contact/info/petsmartcharities/org) and tell them which information you would like to access or which types of contacts you would like to opt out of.
  *   **Mail:**               PetSmart Charities, Inc.

Attn: Privacy Officer

19601 N. 27th Avenue

Phoenix, AZ 85027

  * When mailing or e-mailing us, please include your full name, address, phone number and e-mail address. Also tell us what information you would like to access, change or add to our “opt-out” list. This will help us process your request.

**More Details on How to Opt-Out**

**Direct Mail**

If you do not wish to receive outreach mail directly from us, you may opt out by logging on to PetSmartCharities.org to access and change your profile information and preferences if you have an online account with us, or by calling 1-800-423-PETS (7387) (U.S. residents) as described above.

**Telephone**

If you do not wish to receive outreach telephone calls from us, you may opt out by logging on to PetSmartCharities.org to access and change your profile information and preferences if you have an online account with us, or by calling 1-800-423-PETS (7387) (U.S. residents) as described above. This opt out does not apply to operational phone calls including, for example, confirmation of pet location.

**E-mail**

If you do not wish to receive outreach e-mails from us, you may opt out by logging on to PetSmartCharities.org to access and change your profile information and preferences if you have an online account with us, or by calling 1-800-423-PETS (7387) (U.S. residents) as described above. You may still receive select e-mails from us if you have requested or otherwise accepted them through one of our Service Providers, but you may discontinue these e-mails by canceling your subscription to those services.

You also have the ability to opt out of outreach e-mails on the “unsubscribe” link included in each outreach e-mails or by updating your profile via the “Update Profile” link at the bottom of our outreach e-mails.

**Sharing with Other Organizations (for their outreach purposes)**

If you do not wish us to share the personal information we have collected with other unaffiliated organizations for their outreach purposes, you may opt out by logging on to PetSmartCharities.org to access and change your profile information and preferences if you have an online account with us, or by calling 1-800-423-PETS (7387) (U.S. residents) as described above.

**Mobile**

We may distribute mobile outreach text messages to mobile devices of supporters who have requested this information. 

To opt out of a specific mobile messaging campaign, reply "STOP" to text messages we send you. 

To opt out of all mobile messaging, follow the phone manufacturers’ directions on how to delete cookies or other technology received from our mobile website.  For many phones, you will go to the Settings function to do this.

**Online - PetSmartCharities.org Cookies**

The _Help_ function of your browser should contain instructions to set your computer to accept all cookies, to notify you when a cookie is issued, or to not receive cookies at any time.  If you set your computer to not receive cookies at any time, certain personalized services may not be provided to you, and accordingly, you may not be able to take full advantage of all of the PetSmartCharities.org features (i.e., you will be able to browse the site, but may not be able to use certain features).

**Online - Third-Party Cookies**

Certain organizations provide services that analyze information regarding visits to PetSmartCharities.org.  They use technology such as cookies and web beacons to collect this information.  The _Help_ function of your browser should contain instructions to set your computer to accept all cookies, to notify you when a cookie is issued, or to not receive cookies at any time.  If you set your computer to not receive cookies at any time, certain personalized services may not be provided to you.

**Third-Party Automated Information Collection**

In order to enhance your customer experience, in certain instances we allow third-party companies to collect non-personally identifiable information when you visit our website.  These parties typically use cookies, third-party web beacons, and similar technologies to collect this information. Some browsers have a “do not track” feature that lets you tell websites that you do not want to have your online activities tracked. Neither PetSmart Charities nor its third party providers have a systematic method for ensuring that browser “Do Not Track” requests are consistently honored. However, you may learn more about these activities and how to opt out of the use of your web browsing activity by visiting [http://www.aboutads.info/choices/](http://scanmail.trustwave.com/?c=6406&d=3rHJ1daJAvzKKHOr9Oz-sUPHhCr974ZdODVTrt5H5A&u=http%3a%2f%2fwww%2eaboutads%2einfo%2fchoices%2f).

## California Residents

If you are a California resident and have an established relationship with us, you can request a notice disclosing the categories of personal information we have shared with third parties, for the third parties’ direct outreach purposes, during the preceding calendar year.  To request a notice, please submit your request to PetSmart Charities, Inc., Attn: Privacy Officer, 19601 N. 27th Avenue, Phoenix, AZ 85027.  Please allow 30 days for a response.

## How to Access and Update Your Personal Information

In order to keep your personal information accurate and complete, you may access or update some of it in the following ways:

If you have created a PetSmartCharities.org account, you may log in and update your personal information.   You may also call **1-800-423-PETS (7387)** and ask for the information you are trying to access or change.  Please note that you may need to ask for a manager.

## How Your Personal Information is Protected

### Security Methods

We maintain administrative, technical and physical safeguards to protect your personal information.  When we collect or transmit sensitive information such as a credit or debit card number, we use encryption, access controls, physical security, and other industry standard methods to protect that information.  However, no e-commerce solution, website, database or system is completely secure or “hacker proof.”  You are also responsible for taking reasonable steps to protect your personal information against unauthorized disclosure or misuse.

### E-mail Security

"Phishing" is a scam designed to steal your personal information.  If you receive an e-mail that looks like it is from us asking you for your personal information, do not respond.  We will never request your password, user name, credit card information or other personal information through e-mail.

### Children’s Personal Information

PetSmart Charities recognizes the particular importance of protecting privacy where children are involved.  We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information online from children under the age of 13.

## Questions or Concerns

If you have general questions or concerns about how we use your personal information, please contact us at:

**1\. E-mail:**  [Info[at]petsmartcharities[dot]org](https://web.archive.org/geo-contact/Info/petsmartcharities/org)

**2\. Mail:**

PetSmart Charities, Inc.

Attn: Privacy Officer

19601 North 27th Avenue

Phoenix, AZ 85027

**3\. Phone:**  Toll-free: 1-800-423-PETS (7387) (U.S. Supporters) or (Toll) 1-321-309-9065 (Supporters Outside of the U.S.)  You may need to ask for a manager.

## PetSmart Charities Privacy Policy Scope

This privacy policy applies to all current or former visitor personal information, except for information collected by or provided in connection with completing an application for employment with PetSmart Charities.  Our website may offer links to other sites. If you visit one of these sites, you may want to review the privacy policy on that site.  In addition, you may have visited our website through a link or a banner advertisement on another site.  In such cases, the site you linked from may collect information from people who click on the banner or link.  You may want to refer to the privacy policies on those sites to see how they collect and use this information.

## Updates to this Privacy Policy

If we intend to use or disclose your personal information in any way materially different than what we say in this privacy policy or make any other material changes, we will make reasonable efforts to revise this policy.  If we make any changes to this policy, we will change the “Revised” date below to reflect the date the changes take effect.

_Revised October 2015_
